wyevalegardencentres.co.uk 2015-06-03

# Privacy & Cookie Policy - Wyevale Garden Centres

##  Overview

Wyevale Garden Centres is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This page explains:

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected
  * What organisation is collecting the information
  * How the information is used
  * With whom the information may be shared
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  * What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Wyevale Garden Centres's control
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

###  Under 18s

Children are not eligible to use our services and we ask that minors (under 18 years of age) do not submit any personal information to us. 

###  Information We Collect

Our primary goal in collecting personal information from you is to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and personalised experience while using our website. This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customise our service to make your experience easier and quicker. 

To fully use our website and make purchases, you will need to register as a customer, where you will be required to provide us with your contact information and some other information relating require to process any orders you place with us. We automatically track certain information about you based upon your behaviour on our site. We use this information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand and serve our users. 

We use a web analytics tool to analyse site usage, how our users arrive at our site, what they do on the site, what browser they are using and on what operating system etc. However, this analytics data, collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of our site, is not tied to personally identifiable information.

###  Cookies 

We use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for detailed guidance. 

The following describe the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. Currently we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete [www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk](http://www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk/) cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, "Private Browsing" in Firefox and Safari etc.) 

  * **“Session” Cookies**

       We use a session cookie to remember your login for you and what you’ve put in the shopping basket. These we deem strictly necessary to the working of the website. If these are disabled then various functionality on the site will be broken - including the ability to place orders. Persistent Cookies for Site Analytics & Performance   

  * **Google AdSense**

This cookie is used by Google to report to us how the adverts shown on [www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk](http://www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk/) are performing. User data is all anonymous. You can find out more generally about Google and its policies and principles as regards advertising at [www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/ ](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/)  

  * **DoubleClick (Google)**

This is very similar to the cookie above (both are owned/controlled by Google) but is specific to the display advertising on [www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk](http://www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk/) site. User data is anonymous. As above, you can find out more generally about Google and its policies and principles as regards advertising at [www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/ ](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/)  

  * **Google Analytics**

We use this to understand how the site is being used in order to improve the user experience. User data is all anonymous. You can find out more about Google’s position on privacy as regards its analytics service at [www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview)  

###  Social Buttons

On many of the pages of the site you will see ‘social buttons’. These enable users to share or bookmark the web pages. There are buttons for: Twitter, Google +1, Facebook ‘Like’ and others. In order to implement these buttons, and connect them to the relevant social networks and external sites, there are scripts from domains outside of www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk. You should be aware that these sites are likely to be collecting information about what you are doing all around the internet, including on www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk. So if you click on any of these buttons, these sites will be registering that action and may use that information. In some cases these sites will be registering the fact that you are visiting www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk, and the specific pages you are on, even if you don’t click on the button if you are logged into their services, like Google and Facebook. You should check the respective policies of each of these sites to see how exactly they use your information and to find out how to opt out, or delete, such information.   

###  External Web Services

We use a number of external web services on the [www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk](http://www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk/) site, mostly to display content within our web pages. As with the social buttons we cannot prevent these sites, or external domains, from collecting information on your usage of this embedded content. If you are not logged in to these external services then they will not know who you are but are likely to gather anonymous usage information e.g. number of views, plays, loads etc.   

###  Email Tracking

Some emails that we send you have no tracking in at all e.g. service emails such as order notifications. Other emails we send we put in tracking so that we can tell how much traffic those emails send to our site but we do not know who has clicked so the data is anonymous e.g. our daily newsletter. Some emails we can track, at an individual level, whether the user has opened and clicked on the email. We rarely use the latter information at a personal level, rather we use it to understand open and click rates on our emails to try and improve them. Sometimes we do use the personal information e.g. to re-email people who didn’t click the first time. If you want to be sure that none of your email activity is tracked then you should opt out of Wyevale Garden Centres’s emails which you can do via My Account [www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk/login](http://www.wyevalegardencentres.co.uk/login).   

###  Surveys & Contests

From time to time our site may request information from users via surveys, contests or for a particular service (e.g. newsletter). Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested will include contact information (as supplied to the site during registration) and may include supplementary information as appropriate to the survey or contest. We will use the contact information to notify winners. We will not publish winners' details on the site though on request we will provide details of any winner's name. If the survey or contest has a sponsor then we may share information given by entrants with the sponsor, but only with the user's consent.   

###  Payment Processing

In order to process payments online we require the billing address for the credit card used and your credit card details, which are passed to our payment processor, DataCash. For details of how this information is used, please see Section 3 below.   

###  How We Use Your Information

We use personally identifiable information about you to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyse site usage, to improve our content and product offerings and to customise our site's content, layout, and services. We believe these uses allow us to improve our site and better tailor it to meet our users' needs. 

We use your email address to send you newsletters or other communications that you have requested from the Site. Out of respect for our users we offer an opt-out (see Section 4below). 

We use information in the file we maintain about you, and other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the Site, to resolve any disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Terms & Conditions. At times, we may look across multiple users to identify problems or resolve disputes, and in particular on rare occasions we may evaluate your information to look for users using multiple User IDs or aliases. 

###  Payment Processing

We take online payments for our products and/or services. We use DataCash as our external payment provider. In addition to the information outlined above, we require the billing address of the credit card you use so that we can pass this to DataCash who check the address against the cardholder's details for security purposes. We don't store the credit card details on our server but we do store the billing details and a unique reference to your card details on the DataCash server so that we can process refunds or so you can pay again with the same card more easily. We also use the billing details in case we need to contact you regarding payments e.g. for a failed transaction. DataCash requires that you provide your credit card details to process the transaction. This is done on our secure server and this data is passed immediately and securely to DataCash for their processing. All communications between our servers and DataCash pass over an encrypted connection using SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). 

Your Personal Information is stored in our databases. Please note that the information you enter is not transferred outside of the European Economic Area by Wyevale Garden Centres. There may be circumstances thought where we need to provide appropriate details to third parties to complete the service purchased by you (such as passing your details to a delivery company to effect delivery of goods you have purchased). In these circumstances, we cannot confirm where these third parties store their data. By submitting your information, you consent to this transfer. 

Wyevale Garden Centres complies with the UK Data Protection Act 1998. 

###  Email Communications

As part of the registration process for joining as a customer of Wyevale Garden Centres you have the opportunity to opt in or out to our marketing email communications. If at any stage you wish no longer to receive any emails that you receive from the site you can stop them coming by changing your preferences in the "Newsletter Preferences" section under "My Account". You can also opt-out directly by using the Unsubscribe links contained within these e-mails.   

###  Our Disclosure of Your Information

We do not sell or rent any personally identifiable information about you to any third party. 

Unfortunately, due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. 

By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. We can (and you authorise us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection with an investigation of fraud, Intellectual Property Rights infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose us to legal liability. 

###  Advertisers

We do aggregate personally identifiable information and disclose such information in aggregate to advertisers and for other marketing and promotional purposes. However, in these situations, we do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to personally identify you. There are some cases where we do pass on your personal details, however we only do this if you explicitly agree to this, typically by checking an opt-in checkbox where the default position will be that you do not agree to your details being passed on. For example, where we have events such as Supplier Showcases you may choose to opt-in, at the time of registering for the event, to allow your details to be passed on to those presenting.   

###  Payment and Credit Card Details

As explained above, we store a unique reference against your card details which allows us to process refunds automatically. Only the last four digits of your card number are available to Wyevale Garden Centres admin staff. The first twelve digits are hidden so that Wyevale Garden Centres staff cannot see your full card details. None of your card or billing details are published on the site in any way, nor are they visible to other users on your membership account.   

###  Legal Requests

Wyevale Garden Centres cooperates with law enforcement inquiries and other third parties to enforce laws, Intellectual Property Rights and other rights. Local and international law enforcement agencies can request and may receive your personally identifiable information.   

###  Suppliers and Other Service Providers

From time to time we use third party Suppliers and Service Providers to facilitate our services. Where any Service Provider collects information directly from you (such as the situation where we ask a Service Provider to conduct a survey for us) you will be notified of the involvement of the Supplier or Service Provider, and all information disclosures you make will be strictly optional.   

###  Control of Your Password

Except as specifically permitted by this section, you may not disclose your Wyevale Garden Centres password to any third parties nor share it with any third parties. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personally identifiable information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password by visiting the "Change Password" section in "My Account". 

You may, however, disclose your password to certain third parties with whom Wyevale Garden Centres has entered into specific contractual and technical arrangements designed to safeguard your password, in order to enjoy the benefits of those third parties' services. 

If you wish to change your password you can do so at any time through the "Change Password" section in "My Account" section of the site. 

###  Reviewing and Changing Your Personally Identifiable Information

You can at any time review and change the information you submitted during registration by visiting the "My Account" section of the site. 

You must promptly update your information if it changes. Once posted, you cannot change or remove any public postings made in our forums or other message areas or the feedback area. 

You can at any time ask to see and have removed any information that we have stored on you, though we reserve the right to charge for this service. Please contact Wyevale Garden Centres if you would like your personal information removed. We will retain in our files information you have requested to remove in some circumstances, such as to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Terms & Conditions. Further, such prior information is never completely removed from our databases due to technical constraints and the fact that we back up our systems. Therefore, you should not expect that all of your personally identifiable information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests that it be removed. 

###  Other Information Collectors

Except as otherwise expressly discussed in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your information to other parties, whether they are other members of the Site or other sites throughout the Internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the personal information you disclose to them.   

###  Security

In order to process and help protect your credit card details, we use SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) to secure all communications between the site and you where sensitive information is being exchanged. This includes (but is not limited to) Registration, Login, My Account and Checkout pages. 

On the Wyevale Garden Centres site we use best endeavours to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information but we do not use encryption to store your personally identifiable information. This is because we do not believe that the personal information we currently collect warrants such measures and the accompanying loss of speed experienced. You should be aware that "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. 

###  Changes to Privacy Policy

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will make any changes to this Privacy Policy and post them to our site. It is up to you whether you then continue to use the site and Wyevale Garden Centres’s services following such changes. However, it is assumed that you accept such changes if you continue to use the site and services. If you do not accept such changes then you should stop using Wyevale Garden Centres's site and services and contact us, as per above, should you wish to have any of your details removed.
